<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Year-End Reivew - Category - Hack it!</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/categories/year-end-reivew/</link>
        <description>Year-End Reivew - Category - Hack it!</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lyu@xllyu.org (Xinliang Lyu)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>lyu@xllyu.org (Xinliang Lyu)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 15:42:58 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/year-end-reivew/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Pursue Your Passion and Results Will Be Unexpected — Boosting Your Career Through Independent Learning</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/pursue-physics/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 15:42:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Xinliang Lyu</author>
    <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/pursue-physics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>本文的中文版请点击<a href="https://xllyu.org/pursue-physics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">这里</a></p>
<p>I was trained to be a structural engineer but I want to be a theoretical physicist.</p>
<p>I was major in Japanese when I was a freshman in 2013.
It was exciting and happy to study with so many young girls together: there are about 50 students who were major in Japanese but only five fellows!
For a boy focusing on science side in high school in China, he had hardly seen over 10 girls during his whole high school life.
Such a situation could not be better!
Sadly, the boy read too many science popular books and was more curious about peculiar quantum mechanics, or even string theory at that time, so he decided to change his major.
He first did some research on physics major in his university, but it turned out the people in the physics department look nothing like the characters in his book: Niels Bohr, Wolfgang Pauli, Richard Feynman, Albert Einstein, etc.
As a result, he had to take the second best and went to civil engineering major, hoping he could meet more geek-like people there, since it was (and still is) the department with the most eminent professors and students in the country.
He started his undergraduate training in structure engineering in 2014.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Summary for 2018</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/summary-for-2018/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 03:58:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Xinliang Lyu</author>
    <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/summary-for-2018/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I learned a lot of physics in 2018, and here is a summary!</p>
<h2 id="first-half-the-year">First Half the Year</h2>
<p>In January, I finished <a href="https://courses.edx.org/courses/course-v1:MITx&#43;8.04.1x&#43;3T2017/course/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "><strong>8.04x, Quantum Mechanics</strong></a> an online course provided by MITx and got perfect grades, 92, 94, and 88 for three exams.
8.04x was lectured by Professor Barton Zwiebach, whose doctoral advisor is Murray Gell-mann.
This course introduced basic concepts of Quantum Mechanics and did standard 1-D potential examples, such as square wells, Dirac-delta potential and harmonic oscillators, along with several important theorems for 1-D potential.
Besides, it gave a detailed treatment on scattering states in 1-D, covering topics like time delay, Levinson&rsquo;s theorem and resonance.
The course ended with central potential and Hydrogen Atom.
It was a challenging but rewarding course, and of course, interesting!
What makes this course stand out among all other online courses is its active discussion forum.
I met lots of interesting physics and math geeks there, Mark, Jolyon, Jim, BlueFlow and Jonathan, and the discussion about physics with them made my learn experience vivid and lovely (Actually, I read their discussions in forum most of the time).
Later in September 2018, Jim offered me an unexpected research experience, which was the first time I worked with a real physicist!</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
